and on where exactly is the idbi
disinvestment process headed now that UI
has been have been received by
government of India well I think a
transactional advisor has informed us
that there has been a good response
but we don't actually reveal the names
and the number as per our process now
that we have received the aois there
will be uh
you know qualified and then the process
will move to the as I said the second
stage which includes the fit and proper
verification by The Reserve Bank of
India as well as a due diligence process
under the specific non-disclosure
undertaking to a virtual data room and
the draft sharing
sharing of share purchase agreement
and comments and queries looking into
the different aspects of information
regarding the bank
and then once the bidders are ready go
for financial bidding
in how many weeks the step one of phase
one which is examining the fit and
proper criteria would be concluded
well we don't have those specific
deadlines regarding the processes
but overall I can give you a sense that
the you know depending upon different
transactions the due diligence process
time is different in this case also it
will much depend upon uh you know how
the uh you know things spanned out in
the due diligence virtual data room and
what additional information is required
but usually you know it would be you
know three to four months at least
the final process to go through Mr
Pandey are we talking
months or are we talking about quarters
now we're talking about months
but just to clear the air in FY 23 The
Phase 2 is unlikely to get completed
that's right it will go to fy24
in terms of Interest procedural approval
what is the next stage once you get the
fit and proper indication from Reserve
Bank of India do you think the entire
process of reserve price and bidding
will start parallely
another reserve price fixation takes
place after the financial bids have been
received
it's a Monday what do you mind has been
or potentially could be the biggest
bottleneck in the idbi Strategic
disinvestment so you know earlier it was
covered earlier it was market conditions
for geopolitical conditions but now
things are really falling in place for
us so can I say as of now barring some
Global uncertainty in terms of in
procedural problem uh all decks are
cleared
that's right
Mr Pandey do you think more than
anything it's a else idbi bank will be
more like an important uh
important statement by the government
because it's not an easy asset to divest
we are talking about in bank here which
involves a lot of regulatory approvals
which also involves a strategic buyer
and which also involves a transfer of
government so it's not an easy land
parcel or perhaps a non-strategic
divestment here we are looking at Banks
which in a sense is very crucial and
represents the total commitment of
government towards the disinvestment
process yes I think it's a quite a
unique process in that sense that the
first time we are having a divestment of
a bank
in a in a publicly competitive bidding
process